<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>7 on Dr. Daniel S. Quintana</title>
    <link>/publication_types/7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 7 on Dr. Daniel S. Quintana</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publication_types/7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian alternatives for common null-hypothesis significance tests in psychiatry: A non-technical guide using JASP</title>
      <link>/publication/bmcp2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bmcp2018/</guid>
      <description>Full citation *Quintana, D.S., &amp;amp; Williams, D. R. (2018). Bayesian alternatives for common null-hypothesis significance tests in psychiatry: A non-technical guide using JASP. Open Science Framework, http://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/WUN5V</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for intranasal oxytocin delivery to the brain: recent advances and future perspectives</title>
      <link>/publication/td2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/td2018/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Smerud, K. T., Andreassen, O. A., &amp;amp; Djupesland, P. G. (2018). Evidence for intranasal oxytocin delivery to the brain: recent advances and future perspectives. Open Science Framework, https://dx.doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/FNHX5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxytocin gene networks in the human brain: A gene expression and large-scale fMRI meta-analysis study</title>
      <link>/publication/nc2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/nc2018/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D. S., Rokicki, J., van der Meer, D., Alnæs, D., Kaufmann, T., Palomera, A. C., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Westlye, L. T. Genetic networks of the oxytocin system in the human brain: A gene expression and large-scale fMRI meta-analysis study, Biorxiv, https://doi.org/10.1101/149526</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduced heart rate variability in a treatment-seeking early psychosis sample</title>
      <link>/publication/pr2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pr2018/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Cacciotti-Saija, C., Quintana, DS., Alvares, G., Hickie, I., &amp;amp; Guastella, A. (2017, September 11). Reduced heart rate variability in a treatment-seeking early psychosis sample. Open Science Framework, http://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/NG963</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water consumption as a source of error in the measurement of heart rate variability</title>
      <link>/publication/pj2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pj2018/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Heathers, J., Quintana, DS., Angus, D., Krygier, J., Kemp, A., &amp;amp; de Rosnay, M. (2018, February 28). Water consumption as a source of error in the measurement of heart rate variability. Open Science Framework, http://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/83EXY</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diurnal Variation and Twenty-four Hour Sleep Deprivation do not Alter Supine Heart Rate Variability in Healthy Male Young Adults</title>
      <link>/publication/plos2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/plos2017/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Elvsåshagen, T., Zak, N., Norbom L.B., Pedersen, P.Ø., Quraishi, S.H., Bjørnerud, A., Malt, U.F., Groote, I.R., Kaufmann, T., Andreassen, O.A., Westlye, L.T. (2017). Diurnal Variation and Twenty-four Hour Sleep Deprivation do not Alter Supine Heart Rate Variability in Healthy Male Young Adults. PLOS ONE. 12(2): e0170921, DOI:10.1371/journal.pone.017092</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>