<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Dr. Daniel S. Quintana</title>
    <link>/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Dr. Daniel S. Quintana</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian alternatives for common null-hypothesis significance tests in psychiatry: A non-technical guide using JASP</title>
      <link>/publication/bmcp2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bmcp2018/</guid>
      <description>Full citation *Quintana, D.S., &amp;amp; Williams, D. R. (2018). Bayesian alternatives for common null-hypothesis significance tests in psychiatry: A non-technical guide using JASP. Open Science Framework, http://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/WUN5V</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for intranasal oxytocin delivery to the brain: recent advances and future perspectives</title>
      <link>/publication/td2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/td2018/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Smerud, K. T., Andreassen, O. A., &amp;amp; Djupesland, P. G. (2018). Evidence for intranasal oxytocin delivery to the brain: recent advances and future perspectives. Open Science Framework, https://dx.doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/FNHX5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxytocin gene networks in the human brain: A gene expression and large-scale fMRI meta-analysis study</title>
      <link>/publication/nc2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/nc2018/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D. S., Rokicki, J., van der Meer, D., Alnæs, D., Kaufmann, T., Palomera, A. C., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Westlye, L. T. Genetic networks of the oxytocin system in the human brain: A gene expression and large-scale fMRI meta-analysis study, Biorxiv, https://doi.org/10.1101/149526</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduced heart rate variability in a treatment-seeking early psychosis sample</title>
      <link>/publication/pr2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pr2018/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Cacciotti-Saija, C., Quintana, DS., Alvares, G., Hickie, I., &amp;amp; Guastella, A. (2017, September 11). Reduced heart rate variability in a treatment-seeking early psychosis sample. Open Science Framework, http://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/NG963</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water consumption as a source of error in the measurement of heart rate variability</title>
      <link>/publication/pj2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pj2018/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Heathers, J., Quintana, DS., Angus, D., Krygier, J., Kemp, A., &amp;amp; de Rosnay, M. (2018, February 28). Water consumption as a source of error in the measurement of heart rate variability. Open Science Framework, http://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/83EXY</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Promise of Intranasal Esketamine as a Novel and Effective Antidepressant</title>
      <link>/publication/jamap2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jamap2018/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana DS, Steen NE, Andreassen OA. The Promise of Intranasal Esketamine as a Novel and Effective Antidepressant. JAMA Psychiatry. 2018;75(2):123–124. doi:10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.3738</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting non-significant effects of intranasal oxytocin using equivalence testing</title>
      <link>/publication/pnec2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pnec2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diurnal Variation and Twenty-four Hour Sleep Deprivation do not Alter Supine Heart Rate Variability in Healthy Male Young Adults</title>
      <link>/publication/plos2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/plos2017/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Elvsåshagen, T., Zak, N., Norbom L.B., Pedersen, P.Ø., Quraishi, S.H., Bjørnerud, A., Malt, U.F., Groote, I.R., Kaufmann, T., Andreassen, O.A., Westlye, L.T. (2017). Diurnal Variation and Twenty-four Hour Sleep Deprivation do not Alter Supine Heart Rate Variability in Healthy Male Young Adults. PLOS ONE. 12(2): e0170921, DOI:10.1371/journal.pone.017092</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autism Spectrum Disorders: A meta-analysis of executive function</title>
      <link>/publication/mp2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/mp2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dose-dependent social-cognitive effects of intranasal oxytocin delivered with novel Breath Powered device in adults with autism spectrum disorder: a randomized placebo-controlled double-blind crossover trial</title>
      <link>/publication/tp2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tp2017/</guid>
      <description>More detail can easily be written here using Markdown and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Rate Variability in Psychiatric Disorders, Methodological Considerations, and Recommendations for Future Research</title>
      <link>/publication/ecg2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecg2017/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Kemp, A.H., and Quintana D.S. (2017). Heart Rate Variability in Psychiatric Disorders, Methodological Considerations, and Recommendations for Future Research. In H.F. Jelinek, D.J. Cornforth, and A.H. Khandoker (Eds.), ECG Time Series Variability Analysis (pp. 327-343). Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The correlation between central and peripheral oxytocin concentrations: A systematic review and meta-analysis</title>
      <link>/publication/nbr2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/nbr2017/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Kemp, A.H., and Quintana D.S. (2017). Heart Rate Variability in Psychiatric Disorders, Methodological Considerations, and Recommendations for Future Research. In H.F. Jelinek, D.J. Cornforth, and A.H. Khandoker (Eds.), ECG Time Series Variability Analysis (pp. 327-343). Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxytocin system dysfunction as a common mechanism underlying metabolic syndrome and psychiatric symptoms in schizophrenia and bipolar disorders.</title>
      <link>/publication/fin2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/fin2017/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Dieset, I., Elvsåshagen, T., Westlye, L.T., Andreassen, O.A. (2017). Oxytocin system dysfunction as a common mechanism underlying metabolic syndrome and psychiatric symptoms in schizophrenia and bipolar disorders. Frontiers in Neuroendocrinology DOI:10.1016/j.yfrne.2016.12.004</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustained Attention and Heart Rate Variability in children and adolescents with ADHD</title>
      <link>/publication/biopsychol2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/biopsychol2017/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Griffiths, K.R., Quintana, D.S., Hermens, D.F., Spooner, C., Tsang, T.W., Clarke, S., Kohn, M.R. (2017). Sustained Attention and Heart Rate Variability in children and adolescents with ADHD. Biological Psychology. 124, 11-20 DOI: 10.1016/j.biopsycho.2017.01.00</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliability of basal plasma vasopressin concentrations in healthy male adults</title>
      <link>/publication/an2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/an2017/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Westlye, L.T., Smerud, K., Mahmoud, R. Djupesland, P.G., Andreassen, O.A. (2017). Reliability of basal plasma vasopressin concentrations in healthy male adults. Acta Neuropsychiatrica, 25(9), 315-321.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the hype and hope: critical considerations for intranasal oxytocin research in autism spectrum disorder</title>
      <link>/publication/ar2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ar2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Alvares, G.A., Quintana, D.S., Whitehouse, A. (2017) Beyond the hype and hope: critical considerations for intranasal oxytocin research in autism spectrum disorder. Autism Research, 10(1), https://doi.org/10.1002/aur.1692</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical considerations for reporting and planning heart rate variability case-control studies</title>
      <link>/publication/pp2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pp2017/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S. (2017). Statistical considerations for reporting and planning heart rate variability case-control studies. Psychophysiology, 54(3), 344–349.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of oxytocin administration on brain activity: a systematic review and meta-analysis protocol</title>
      <link>/publication/sr2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sr2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Elvsåshagen, T., Zak, N., Norbom L.B., Pedersen, P.Ø., Quraishi, S.H., Bjørnerud, A., Malt, U.F., Groote, I.R., Kaufmann, T., Andreassen, O.A., Westlye, L.T. (2017). Diurnal Variation and Twenty-four Hour Sleep Deprivation do not Alter Supine Heart Rate Variability in Healthy Male Young Adults. PLOS ONE. 12(2): e0170921, DOI:10.1371/journal.pone.0170921</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribution of oxytocin receptor polymorphisms to amygdala activation in schizophrenia spectrum disorders</title>
      <link>/publication/bjpo2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bjpo2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Haram, M., Bettella, F., Brandt C.L., Quintana, D.S., Nerhus, M., Bjella, T., Djurovic, S., Westlye, L.T., Andreassen, O.A., Melle, I., Tesli, M. (2016). Contribution of oxytocin receptor polymorphisms to amygdala activation in schizophrenia spectrum disorders. British Journal of Psychiatry Open, 2(8)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resting-state heart rate variability is related to respiratory frequency in individuals with severe mental illness but not healthy controls</title>
      <link>/publication/scirep2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/scirep2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Elstad, M., Kaufmann, T., Brandt C.L., Haatveit, B., Nerhus, M., Haram, M., Westlye, L.T., Andreassen, O.A. (2016). Resting-state heart rate variability is related to respiratory frequency in individuals with severe mental illness but not healthy controls. Scientific Reports, 6(37212)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worry is associated with robust reductions in heart rate variability: A transdiagnostic study of anxiety psychopathology</title>
      <link>/publication/bmcp2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bmcp2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Chalmers, J.A., Heathers, J.A.J., Abbott, M.J., Kemp A.H., and Quintana, D.S. (2016). Worry is associated with robust reductions in heart rate variability: A transdiagnostic study of anxiety psychopathology. BMC Psychology, 4(32).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines for Reporting Articles on Psychiatry and Heart rate variability (GRAPH): Recommendations to advance research communication</title>
      <link>/publication/tp2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tp2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Alvares, G.A., Heathers, J.A.J. (2016). Guidelines for Reporting Articles on Psychiatry and Heart rate variability (GRAPH): Recommendations to advance research communication. Translational Psychiatry, 6(5), doi:10.1038/tp.2016.73</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low dose intranasal oxytocin delivered with Breath Powered device dampens amygdala response to emotional stimuli: A peripheral effect-controlled within-subjects randomised dose-response fMRI trial</title>
      <link>/publication/pnec2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pnec2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Westlye, L.T., Alnæs, D., Rustan, Ø.G., Kaufmann, T., Smerud, K., Mahmoud, R. Djupesland, P.G., and Andreassen, O.A. (2016). Low dose intranasal oxytocin delivered with Breath Powered device dampens amygdala response to emotional stimuli: A peripheral effect-controlled within-subjects randomised dose-response fMRI trial. Psychoneuroendocrinology, 69, 180-188. doi:10.1016/j.psyneuen.2016.04.010</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxytocin: How does this neuropeptide change our social behavior?</title>
      <link>/publication/fym2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/fym2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S. and Alvares, G. A. (2016). Oxytocin: How does this neuropeptide change our social behavior? Frontiers for Young Minds, 4(7). doi: 10.3389/frym.2016.00007</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The relationship between central and peripheral oxytocin concentrations: a systematic review and meta-analysis protocol</title>
      <link>/publication/sr2016b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/sr2016b/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Valstad, M., Alvares, G.A., Andreassen, O.A., Westlye, L. T., and Quintana, D.S. (2016). The relationship between central and peripheral oxytocin concentrations: a systematic review and meta-analysis protocol. Systematic Reviews, 5, doi:10.1186/s13643-016-0225-5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A meta-analysis of Theory of Mind in Alcohol Use Disorders</title>
      <link>/publication/aaa2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/aaa2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation RC Onuoha, DS Quintana, M Lyvers, AJ Guastella; A Meta-analysis of Theory of Mind in Alcohol Use Disorders, Alcohol and Alcoholism, 51(4), 410–415, https://doi.org/10.1093/alcalc/agv137</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Article Mentions and Citations: An Exploratory Analysis of Publications in The American Journal of Psychiatry</title>
      <link>/publication/ajp2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ajp2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S. &amp;amp; Doan N.T. (2016). Twitter Article Mentions and Citations: An Exploratory Analysis of Publications in The American Journal of Psychiatry. The American Journal of Psychiatry, 173(2), 194. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2015.15101341</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The promise and pitfalls of intranasally administering psychopharmacological agents for the treatment of psychiatric disorders</title>
      <link>/publication/mp2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/mp2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Guastella, A.J., Westlye, L.T., Andreassen, O.A. (2016). The promise and pitfalls of intranasally administering psychopharmacological agents for the treatment of psychiatric disorders. Molecular Psychiatry, 21(1)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduced heart rate variability in schizophrenia and bipolar disorder compared to healthy controls</title>
      <link>/publication/aps2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/aps2016/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Westlye, L.T., Kaufmann, T., Rustan, Ø.G., Brandt, C.L., Haatveit, B., Steen, N.S., Andreassen, O.A. (2016). Reduced heart rate variability in schizophrenia and bipolar disorder compared to healthy controls. Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavia, 133(1)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From pre-registration to publication: a nontechnical primer for conducting a meta-analysis to synthesize correlational data</title>
      <link>/publication/fip2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/fip2015/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S. (2015). From pre-registration to publication: a nontechnical primer for conducting a meta-analysis to synthesize correlational data. Frontiers in Psychology 6:1549. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2015.01549</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomic nervous system dysfunction in psychiatric disorders and the impact of psychotropic medications: a systematic review and meta-analysis</title>
      <link>/publication/jpn2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jpn2015/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Alvalres, G.A., Quintana, D.S., Hickie, I.B., and Guastella, A.J., (in press). Autonomic Nervous System Dysfunction in Psychiatric Disorders and the Impact of Psychotropic Medications: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Journal of Psychiatry and Neuroscience, 41(2), DOI: 10.1503/jpn.140217</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold face test-induced increases in heart rate variability are abolished by engagement in a social cognition task</title>
      <link>/publication/jop2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jop2015/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Iorfino, F., Alvares, G.A., Guastella, A.J., and Quintana, D.S. (2015). Cold face test-induced increases in heart rate variability are abolished by engagement in a social cognition task. Journal of Psychophysiology, 30, 38-46,https://doi.org/10.1027/0269-8803/a000152</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intranasal oxytocin mechanisms can be better understood but its effects on social cognition and behavior are not to be sniffed at</title>
      <link>/publication/bp2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bp2015/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Iorfino, F., Alvares, G.A., Guastella, A.J., and Quintana, D.S. (2015). Cold face test-induced increases in heart rate variability are abolished by engagement in a social cognition task. Journal of Psychophysiology, 30, 38-46,https://doi.org/10.1027/0269-8803/a000152</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Rate Variability during Adolescent and Adult Social Interactions: a Meta-Analysis</title>
      <link>/publication/bpsychol2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bpsychol2015/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Shahrestani, S. Stewart, E. M., Quintana, D.S., Hickie, I. B., Guastella, A. J. (2015). Heart Rate Variability during Adolescent and Adult Social Interactions: a Meta-Analysis. Biological Psychology, 105, 43-50</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low dose oxytocin delivered intranasally with Breath Powered device affects social-cognitive behavior: a randomized 4-way crossover trial with nasal cavity dimension assessment</title>
      <link>/publication/tp2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tp2015/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Westlye, L.T., Rustan, Ø.G., Tesli, N., Poppy, C, Smevik, H., Tesli, M., Røine, M., Mahmoud, R., Smerud, K., Djupesland, P.G., and Andreassen, O.A. (2015). Low dose oxytocin delivered intranasally with Breath Powered device affects social-cognitive behavior: a randomized 4-way crossover trial with nasal cavity dimension assessment. Translational Psychiatry, 5, e602</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do delivery routes of intranasally administered oxytocin account for observed effects on social cognition and behavior? A two-level model</title>
      <link>/publication/nbr2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/nbr2015/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Alvares, G. A., Hickie, I.H., Guastella, A. J. (2015). Do delivery routes of intranasally administered oxytocin account for observed effects on social cognition and behavior? A two-level model. Neuroscience &amp;amp; Biobehavioral Reviews, 49, 182-192, doi:10.1016/j.neubiorev.2014.12.011</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major depressive disorder with melancholia displays robust alterations in resting state heart rate and its variability: Implications for future morbidity and mortality</title>
      <link>/publication/fip2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/fip2014/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Kemp A.H., Quintana D.S., Quinn C., Hopkinson P., Harris A. (2014). Major depressive disorder with melancholia displays robust alterations in resting state heart rate and its variability: Implications for future morbidity and mortality. Frontiers in Psychology, 5:1387. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2014.01387</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations in the assessment of heart rate  variability in biobehavioral research</title>
      <link>/publication/fip2014b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/fip2014b/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana D.S. &amp;amp; Heathers, J.A.J. (2014). Considerations in the assessment of heart rate variability in biobehavioral research. Frontiers in Psychology, 5:805. doi:10.3389/fpsyg.2014.00805</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anxiety disorders are associated with reduced heart rate variability: A meta-analysis</title>
      <link>/publication/fipsychiatry2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/fipsychiatry2014/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Chalmers J, Quintana D.S., Abbott M.J. and Kemp A.H. (2014). Anxiety disorders are associated with reduced heart rate variability: A meta-analysis. Frontiers in Psychiatry, 5:80. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2014.00080</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytokine aberrations in Autism Spectrum Disorder: A systematic review and meta-analysis</title>
      <link>/publication/mp2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/mp2014/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Masi, A., Quintana, D.S., Glozier, N., Lloyd, A., Hickie, I.B., Guastella, A.J. (2014). Cytokine aberrations in Autism Spectrum Disorder: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Molecular Psychiatry, 20, 440–446. doi: 10.1038/mp.2014.59</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart rate variability during social interactions in children with and without psychopathology: a meta-analysis</title>
      <link>/publication/jcpp2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jcpp2014/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Shahrestani, S., Stewart, E. M., Quintana, D.S., Hickie, I. B., Guastella, A.J. (2014). Heart rate variability during social interactions in children with and without psychopathology: a meta-analysis. Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, 55(9), doi: 10.1111/jcpp.12226</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moderate alcohol intake is related to increased heart rate variability</title>
      <link>/publication/pp2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pp2013/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Guastella, A.J., McGregor, I.S, Hickie, I. B., Kemp, A.H. (2013). Moderate alcohol intake is related to increased heart rate variability. Psychophysiology. 50(12), 1202-1208.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduced Heart Rate Variability in Social Anxiety Disorder: Associations with Gender and Symptom Severity</title>
      <link>/publication/plos2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/plos2013/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Alvares, G.A., Quintana, D.S., Kemp, A.H., van Zweiten, A., Balleine, B. W., Hickie, I. G., &amp;amp; Guastella, A.J. (2013). Reduced Heart Rate Variability in Social Anxiety Disorder: Associations with Gender and Symptom Severity. PLoS One, 8(7): e70468. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0070468.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The relationship between mental and physical health: Insights from the study of heart rate variability</title>
      <link>/publication/ijp2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ijp2013/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Kemp, A.H. &amp;amp; Quintana, D.S. (2013). The relationship between mental and physical health: Insights from the study of heart rate variability. International Journal of Psychophysiology, 89(3), 288-296</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A role for autonomic cardiac control in the effects of oxytocin on social behaviour and psychiatric illness</title>
      <link>/publication/fin2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/fin2013/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Kemp, A.H., Alvares, G.A., Guastella, A.J. (2013). A role for autonomic cardiac control in the effects of oxytocin on social behaviour and psychiatric illness. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 7:48; doi: 10.3389/fnins.2013.00048.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart rate variability predicts alcohol craving in alcohol dependent outpatients: Further evidence for HRV as a psychophysiological marker of self-regulation</title>
      <link>/publication/dad2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/dad2013/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Guastella, A.J., McGregor, I.S., Hickie, I.B., &amp;amp; Kemp, A.H. (2013). Heart rate variability predicts alcohol craving in alcohol dependent outpatients: Further evidence for HRV as a psychophysiological marker of self-regulation. Drug and Alcohol Dependence, 132(1), 395-398</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A meta-analysis on the impact of alcohol dependence on short-term resting state heart rate variability: Implications for cardiovascular risk</title>
      <link>/publication/acer2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/acer2013/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana D.S., McGregor, I.S., Guastella, A.J., Malhi, G.S., Kemp A.H, (2013). A meta-analysis on the impact of alcohol dependence on short-term resting state heart rate variability: Implications for cardiovascular risk. Alcoholism: Clinical and Experimental Research, 37(S1), E23-E29.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart rate variability is associated with emotion recognition: Direct evidence for a relationship between the autonomic nervous system and social cognition</title>
      <link>/publication/ijp2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ijp2012/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana, D.S., Guastella, A.J., Outhred, T., Hickie, I. B., Kemp, A.H. (2012). Heart rate variability is associated with emotion recognition: Direct evidence for a relationship between the autonomic nervous system and social cognition. International Journal of Psychophysiology, 86(2); 168-172</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matter Over Mind: A Randomised-Controlled Trial of Single-Session Biofeedback Training on Performance Anxiety and Heart Rate Variability in Musicians</title>
      <link>/publication/plos2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/plos2012/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Wells, R., Outhred, T., Heathers, J.A.J., Quintana, D.S., Kemp, A.H., (2012) Matter Over Mind: A Randomised-Controlled Trial of Single-Session Biofeedback Training on Performance Anxiety and Heart Rate Variability in Musicians. PLoS ONE, 7(10): e46597.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Validity of Using the Polar RS800 Heart Rate Monitor for Heart Rate Variability Research</title>
      <link>/publication/ejap2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ejap2012/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Quintana D.S., Heathers, J.A.J., Kemp A.H. (2012). On the Validity of Using the Polar RS800 Heart Rate Monitor for Heart Rate Variability Research. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 112; 4179-4180.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxytocin increases heart rate variability in humans at rest: Implications for social approach-related motivation and capacity for social engagement</title>
      <link>/publication/plos2012b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/plos2012b/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Kemp A.H., Quintana D.S., Kuhnert, R.L., Griffiths, K., Hickie, I.B. Guastella, A.J., Malhi, G.S., (2012). Oxytocin increases heart rate variability in humans at rest: Implications for social approach-related motivation and capacity for social engagement. PLoS One, 7(8); e44014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Depression, Comorbid Anxiety Disorders, and Heart Rate Variability in Physically Healthy, Unmedicated Patients: Implications for Cardiovascular Risk</title>
      <link>/publication/plos2012c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/plos2012c/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Kemp A.H., Quintana D.S., Felmingham K.L., Matthews S., Jelinek H.F. (2012) Depression, Comorbid Anxiety Disorders, and Heart Rate Variability in Physically Healthy, Unmedicated Patients: Implications for Cardiovascular Risk. PLoS ONE, 7(2): e30777.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complex correlation measure as a sensitive indicator of risk for sudden cardiac death in patients with depression</title>
      <link>/publication/cic2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cic2011/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Jelinek, H.F., Khandoker, A.H., Quintana, D.S., Imam, M.H., Kemp, A.H. (2011). Complex correlation measure as a sensitive indicator of risk for sudden cardiac death in patients with depression. Computing in Cardiology, 38.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is heart rate variability reduced in depression without cardiovascular disease?</title>
      <link>/publication/bp2011b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bp2011b/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Kemp, A.H., Quintana, D.S., Gray, M. (2011). Is heart rate variability reduced in depression without cardiovascular disease? Biological Psychiatry, 69; e3-e4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitors on Heart Rate Variability: Methodological Issues, Medical Comorbidity, and Clinical Relevance</title>
      <link>/publication/bp2011a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bp2011a/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Kemp, A.H., Quintana, D.S., Mahli, G.S. (2011). Effects of Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitors on Heart Rate Variability: Methodological Issues, Medical Comorbidity, and Clinical Relevance. Biological Psychiatry, 69(8); e25-e26.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Depression and Antidepressant Treatment on Heart Rate Variability: A review and Meta-analysis</title>
      <link>/publication/bp2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bp2010/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Kemp, A.H., Quintana, D.S., Gray, M., Felmingham, K., Brown, K., Gatt, J. (2010). Impact of Depression and Antidepressant Treatment on Heart Rate Variability: A review and Meta-analysis. Biological Psychiatry, 67; 1067-1074</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of depression heterogeneity on attention: An auditory oddball event related potential study</title>
      <link>/publication/jad2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jad2010/</guid>
      <description>Full citation Kemp, A. H., Pe Benito, L., Quintana, D.S., Clark, C. R., McFarlane, A., Mayur, P., Harris, A., Boyce, P., Williams, L. M. (2010). Impact of depression heterogeneity on attention: An auditory oddball event related potential study. Journal of Affective Disorders, 123 (1); 202-207</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>